<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on Notre Dame Linux Users Group</title>
    <link>http://ndlug.org/member/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on Notre Dame Linux Users Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ndlug.org/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zephan M. Enciso</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/zenciso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/zenciso/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Zephan Enciso, a junior studying Computer Engineering and Electrical Engineering. I typically run Arch Linux with KDE and/or i3-gaps. Most LUGites know me as a huge computer hardware nerd, but outside of LUG, I enjoy olympic archery, playing violin, taking pictures, or pwning noobs in video games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryan Ingwersen (bingwers)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/bingwers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/bingwers/</guid>
      <description>I am a first year student at Notre Dame who just joined LUG. More information to come!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parker Chun (pchun)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/pchun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 18:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/pchun/</guid>
      <description>My name is Parker Chun. I am a current sophomore studying computer science at the University of Notre Dame.

Apart from my computer science related coursework, extracurriculars, and interests, I like to dance, play the piano, and play basketball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bradley Budden (bbudden)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/bbudden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/bbudden/</guid>
      <description>My name is Brad Budden. I am a current sophomore studying computer science at the University of Notre Dame. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly what field of computer science I will be most interested in, but I enjoy learning about linux and have fun with embedded systems programming for arduinos. Last summer, I studied abroad in Rome, taking classes in quantum engineering and visual programming. I and was able to travel all over Italy and to Greece, Switzerland, and Sweden Next spring I hope to participate in the Notre Dame Silicon Valley Semester, a program offered by ND out in the valley for students looking to take relevant courses and work at local companies/startups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eamon Lopez Marmion (elopez7)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/elopez7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/elopez7/</guid>
      <description>My name is Eamon. I am a (non dues-paying) member of NDLUG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathryn Hund (khund)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/khund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/khund/</guid>
      <description>My name&amp;rsquo;s Kathryn Hund, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently a freshman at Saint Mary&amp;rsquo;s.
I&amp;rsquo;m from Florida (on the east coast - right in the destruction path of every hurricane). My intended major is Computing &amp;amp; Applied Mathematics.
I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to participating in NDLUG to get more familiar with both Linux in particular and open source in general.
My current goals are to become an active contributor to open source, and to participate in Google Summer of Code at least once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noah Yoshida (nyoshida)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/nyoshida/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/nyoshida/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am Noah. I order pizza for Lug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike &#39;AndroidKitKat&#39; Eisemann</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/androidkitkat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/androidkitkat/</guid>
      <description>Hiya, I&amp;rsquo;m Mike Eisemann, but most of you probably know me as AndroidKitKat. I&amp;rsquo;m the current Vice President of NDLUG. I am a computer science major and thinking about minoring in Japanese. Some of my favorite things are VR video games and learning Japanese. If you want to read more about me, check out my personal website at https://www.michaeleisemann.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dalton Dove (ddove)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/ddove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/ddove/</guid>
      <description>Hello I am Dalton Dove and I am a sophomore in computer engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavin Inglis (ginglis)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/ginglis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/ginglis/</guid>
      <description>My name is Gavin Inglis. I am a current junior studying computer science at the University of Notre Dame. My main interests are Systems Programming and Linux, but I enjoy reading and learning about all things computer science.

I am a SysAdmin and Secretary for the Notre Dame Linux Users Group. I most recently worked for Accenture on a project in the Public Health space in Cincinnati. I was introduced to Salesforce tools, and I had experience developing and administrating in Salesforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacob Mazur (jmazur2)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/jmazur2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/jmazur2/</guid>
      <description>My name is Jacob Mazur. I am a sophomore studying computer engineering at the University of Notre Dame.

I am interested in most things related to technology, particularly computer hardware.

  *That&#39;s me all the way on the left, pictured with Logan, Noah, and AKK* --</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Kuebler (jkuebler)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/jkuebler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/jkuebler/</guid>
      <description>
My name is Joe Kuebler. I am a current sophomore studying computer science at the University of Notre Dame. Some things i enjoy outisde of cimputer science are soccer, politics, and traveling. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keegan MacDonell (kmacdon7)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/kmacdon7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/kmacdon7/</guid>
      <description>
My name is Keegan MacDonell. I am a current sophomore studying computer science at the University of Notre Dame. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nick Locascio (nlocasci)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/nlocasci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/nlocasci/</guid>
      <description>My name is Nick Locascio. I am a sophomore computer science major here at Notre Dame and I am originally from Denver, Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nolan McShea (nmcshea)</title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/nmcshea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/nmcshea/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Nolan McShea and I&amp;rsquo;m a sophomore majoring in Computer Science! I recently just dropped my digital marketing minor so I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I&amp;rsquo;m minoring in digital marketing anymore, which stinks but it was boring so I don&amp;rsquo;t care. My college-long objective is to make a video game! (I wanna finish it by the time I graduate) So right now I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn digital music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://ndlug.org/member/xxie6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ndlug.org/member/xxie6/</guid>
      <description>Cynthia Xie</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>