<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Notre Dame Linux Users Group</title>
    <link href="https://ndlug.org"/>
    <link href="https://ndlug.org" rel="self"/>
    <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://ndlug.org</id>
    <author>
        <name>NDLUG</name>
        <email>ndlug@nd.edu</email>
    </author>
    <generator>generate-feed.sh</generator>
    <entry>
        <title>Happy Birthday, Linux!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan (write-up), Paul Gierl (minutes)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-09-15-happy-birthday-linux.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-09-15-happy-birthday-linux.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>After a long hiatus, we held our first in-person meeting of the year. The theme: celebrating the 30th anniversary of Linus Torvald’s email announcing his now-famous operating system. Professor Bui kicked off the meeting with a brief <a href=https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1xNAF_xXq0gYsokWBv1xVn70Y-1P0F-sgW6ObZliPXxg/edit?usp=sharing>presentation</a> about the club, its values, and the origins of Linux and free software. Then our president, Nolan, outlined some upcoming club events, such as an internship panel and an “open sauce in the wild” meeting. Officers led a discussion about members’ favorite Linux memories, which ranged from triumphant first installs on bare metal to PEBKAC-induced system breakages. No birthday party is complete without a cake (or party hats!), which was promptly cut and consumed over delightful conversation. With a headcount of 15 and the enthusiasm of ten times that, it’s safe to call this meeting a success.</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/discussion.jpg alt=members discussing linux memories></p> <p><img src=../assets/img/cake.jpg alt=cake!></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Linux at Work</title>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bui (write-up), Paul Gierl (minutes)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-09-22-linux-at-work.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-09-22-linux-at-work.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>For our second meeting, we invited a number of former and current LUG members to come and talk about their experiences using Linux and Open Source during their internships or in their careers.</p> <p>Guest Speakers included:</p> <ol type=1> <li>Michael Eisemann (<a href=https://www.nsa.gov/>NSA</a>, <em>LUG President Emeritus</em>)</li> <li>Sam Battalio (<a href=https://www.purestorage.com/>Pure Storage</a>, <em>LUG Officer emeritus</em>)</li> <li>Conor Nailos (<a href=https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en.html>Deloitte</a>, <em>LUG Officer emeritus</em>)</li> <li>Emory Smith (<a href=https://lucata.com/>Lucata</a>, <em>LUG Member emeritus</em>)</li> <li>Zephan Enciso (<a href=https://cse.nd.edu>ND CSE</a>, <em>LUG Officer emeritus</em>)</li> <li>Nolan McShea (<a href=https://www.hp.com>HP</a>, <em>LUG President</em>)</li> <li>John Sullivan (<a href=https://aerospace.org/>Aerospace Corporation</a>, <em>LUG Officer</em>)</li> <li>Joshua Tabar (Startup, <em>LUG Ally</em>)</li> <li>Jacob Mozdzen (<a href=https://microsoft.com>Microsoft</a>, <em>LUG Ally</em>)</li> </ol> <p>Along with our 9 panelists, we had about 15 members in attendance to learn and discuss Linux and open source with our guest speakers. Highlights from the meeting include:</p> <ul> <li>Linux commands come in handy such as grep, cut, and others.</li> <li>Operating system principles help to understand the ideas in industry.</li> <li>Even navigating at a basic level on a Linux machine is extremely helpful, especially if you know how to read documentation and figure things out. </li> <li>You will inevitably hit red tape because some companies don’t want you doing whatever you want. Find ways to work around it or have other projects  to work on as well.</li> <li>Linux+ certificate may not matter as much. It can be better just by doing and working on projects. It depends a bit on the industry too - for example it may be more relevant for consultants to have certifications.</li> </ul> <p>Of course, you can catch all the wisdom of our panelists by watching the record on <a href=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pElotTEEm6Q>YouTube</a>:</p> <div style=text-align: center> <iframe width=560 height=315 src=https://www.youtube.com/embed/pElotTEEm6Q title=YouTube video player frameborder=0 allow=accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture allowfullscreen> </iframe> </div> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Open Sauce in the Wild</title>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Gierl (write-up), Paul Gierl (minutes)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-09-29-open-sauce-in-the-wild.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-09-29-open-sauce-in-the-wild.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>For our third meeting we gave our LUG members an assignment to share their favorite FOSS that they have used or use regularly. We began with an example of Linux and open source software in action by watching a video about the Ingenuity helicopter that was attached to the Perseverance rover.</p> <p>There were many interesting and intriguing pieces of software shared amongst the group. It was fun to see how many different options there are out there in the wild. Here are the top FOSS used by the 15 LUG members in attendance:</p> <ol type=1> <li><a href=https://www.android.com/>Android</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/>Firefox</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.gimp.org/>GIMP</a></li> <li><a href=https://shotcut.org/>Shotcut</a></li> <li><a href=https://xournalpp.github.io/>Xournal++</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.cgeo.org/>c:geo</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.blender.org/>Blender</a></li> <li><a href=https://apps.ankiweb.net/>Anki</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.wireguard.com/>Wireguard</a></li> <li><a href=https://reactjs.org/>React</a></li> <li><a href=https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/terminal/>Windows Terminal</a></li> <li><a href=https://qutebrowser.org/>Qutebrowser</a></li> <li><a href=https://weechat.org/>Weechat</a></li> <li><a href=https://i3wm.org/>i3</a></li> <li><a href=https://newsboat.org/>Newsboat</a></li> <li><a href=https://radicale.org/3.0.html>Radicale</a> + <a href=https://calcurse.org/>calcurse</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/>Emacs</a></li> <li><a href=https://inkscape.org/>Inkscape</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.libreoffice.org/>LibreOffice</a></li> <li><a href=https://bitwarden.com/>Bitwarden</a></li> <li><a href=https://joplinapp.org/>Joplin</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.minetest.net/>Minetest</a></li> </ol> <p>Many of these are used because of their freedom and openness. They allow users to customize their experience in any way they wish; to improve it for their needs. There are plenty of free and open software alternatives to applications from big tech companies such as Google, Apple, and the like. A lot of these are lightweight and quick programs that have fanbases to help with whatever issues occur. In celebration of FOSS we had Raising Cane’s at the meeting!</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/2021-09-29-sauce.jpg alt=Saucy!></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hacktoberfest is Here</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan (write-up), Paul Gierl (minutes)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-10-06-hacktoberfest.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-10-06-hacktoberfest.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In our first meeting of October, we learned about and discussed our plans for <a href=https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/>Hacktoberfest</a>, an event which its host <a href=https://www.digitalocean.com/>Digital Ocean</a> describes as a “month-long celebration of open source software<a href=#fn1 class=footnote-ref id=fnref1><sup>1</sup></a>.” Now in its eighth year, the event invites participants to make contributions to opted-in repositories on <a href=https://github.com/>GitHub</a> or <a href=https://gitlab.com/>GitLab</a>. The first 50,000 people to make four approved pull requests earn a (free!) t-shirt and stickers. Professor Bui gave a presentation on how to use <a href=https://git-scm.com/>Git</a>, a distributed version control system that is integral to many software projects and to the Hacktoberfest workflow.</p> <p>In addition to promoting contributions to projects broadly, our club has created a repository in which members can collaborate on solving a series of programming challenges. <a href=https://github.com/NDLUG/control-alt-delete>Control-Alt-Delete</a> invites programmers to complete five challenges to help <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tux_(mascot)>Tux</a> escape <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BSD_Daemon>Beastie</a>’s <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FreeBSD_jail>jail</a>! Welcome contributions include new solutions, improvements to existing solutions, testing, documentation, and additions to the story. We’ve already had some creative solutions from members in languages such as <a href=https://github.com/NDLUG/control-alt-delete/blob/master/challenge00/solution-dblitt.js>JavaScript</a>, <a href=https://github.com/NDLUG/control-alt-delete/blob/master/challenge01/solution-herbertmcsnout.hs>Haskell</a>, and <a href=https://github.com/NDLUG/control-alt-delete/blob/master/challenge02/solution-jabbott4.c>C</a>. Happy Hacktoberfest – now get hacking!</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/hacktoberfest-tux-and-beastie.png alt=Hacktoberfest logo with Tux and Beastie></p> <section class=footnotes> <hr /> <ol> <li id=fn1><p><a href=https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/open-source-misses-the-point.html>Not to be confused</a> with <a href=https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html>free software</a>.<a href=#fnref1 class=footnote-back>↩</a></p></li> </ol> </section> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hacktoberfest Show and Tell</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-10-27-show-and-tell.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-10-27-show-and-tell.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>After a two week hiatus due to midterms and fall break, we met to discuss our experiences participating in Hacktoberfest. In our <a href=https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-10-06-hacktoberfest.html>previous meeting</a>, we had outlined what Hacktoberfest is and how to get involved, so this meeting served as a bookend to wrap-up and share what we did during the month.</p> <p>Most of our contributions were to the <a href=https://github.com/NDLUG/control-alt-delete>Control-Alt-Delete</a> repository, the set of collaborative programming challenges centered around a story about <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tux_(mascot)>Tux</a> and <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BSD_Daemon>Beastie</a>. We had contributions in several different programming languages, as well as some fun art made with <a href=https://www.gimp.org/>GIMP</a>. As busy as this month was, we had multiple members reach the 4 contribution threshold to order a free t-shirt. Free is good, in both software and t-shirts!</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/hacktoberfest-h.png alt=Hacktoberfest H logo></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>We Installed Arch, BTW</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-11-03-arch-install.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-11-03-arch-install.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Of all the Linux distributions out there, perhaps none is more memed than <a href=https://archlinux.org/>Arch Linux</a>. Arch is billed as a lightweight and customizable distro that tries to abide by the <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle>KISS</a> philosophy.<a href=#fn1 class=footnote-ref id=fnref1><sup>1</sup></a> Some of its most compelling offerings are the high quality <a href=https://wiki.archlinux.org/>wiki</a>, which is applicable for users of every distro, and the <a href=https://aur.archlinux.org/>AUR</a>, a large collection of build scripts for software outside the official package repositories.</p> <p>Installation of Arch is sometimes considered difficult, because it requires more involvment from the user than other distros. But in reality, anyone can install it by following the well-written <a href=https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Installation_guide>installation guide</a>. Our club decided to install it together in order to learn more about the steps of the process that more traditional installers do on the user’s behalf.</p> <p>We used <a href=https://github.com/wimpysworld/quickemu>Quickemu</a>, a wrapper around <a href=https://www.qemu.org/>QEMU</a>, to easily spin up a virtual machine for an Arch install. Then we proceeded through the installation steps, which included connecting to the internet, updating the system clock, creating and formatting and mounting partitions, and using the <a href=https://man.archlinux.org/man/pacstrap.8>pacstrap</a> utility to install the base set of packages. After some more configuration, setting our root password, and choosing our bootloader, we managed to install <a href=https://www.x.org/>Xorg</a> to get a minimal graphical interface. From here we could install a desktop environment or a more complete window manager than the default one, but that can be a task for a future meeting.</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/archmemes.png alt=Arch Linux memes></p> <section class=footnotes> <hr /> <ol> <li id=fn1><p>For a different distribution’s take on this principle, see <a href=https://kisslinux.org/>Kiss Linux</a><a href=#fnref1 class=footnote-back>↩</a></p></li> </ol> </section> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Spring Courses Livestream</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-11-10-spring-courses.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-11-10-spring-courses.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>This week’s meeting took the form of a livestream on our <a href=https://www.twitch.tv/ndlug>Twitch channel</a>. Registration for <a href=https://registrar.nd.edu/students/registration_spring.php>Spring 2022</a> is fast approaching, so President Nolan, Vice President Paul, and Advisor Professor Bui led a discussion of the <a href=https://cse.nd.edu/>CSE Department</a>’s course offerings for the upcoming semester.</p> <p>Of particular interest were the elective courses, which include “Computer Graphics”, “Hardware for Learning,” and “Open Source Software Development.” Current undergrads, graduate students, and alumni kept the Twitch chat busy with questions, comments, and recommendations. I’m sure this stream will be of great use to anyone unsure of what to take next semester. Because this blog post’s author is not a CSE major, that’s about all the detail I can give you. Go watch <a href=https://www.twitch.tv/videos/1201855476>the stream</a> yourself to find out more.</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/sp22-courses-stream.png alt=Twitch livestream screenshot></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Ricing Unix</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan (write-up), Paul Gierl (minutes)</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-11-17-ricing-unix.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-11-17-ricing-unix.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>One major focus among users of Linux (and other Unix-like operating systems) is the customization of their workflow and visual environment, often referred to as “<strong>ricing</strong>.” Our members met this week to show off and compare their rices, and eat some delicous fried rice!</p> <p>We had a vast range of setups, such as <a href=https://www.gnome.org/>GNOME</a> desktops tweaked with extensions, minimal window managers like <a href=https://i3wm.org/>i3wm</a> and <a href=https://github.com/baskerville/bspwm>bspwm</a>, and of course an <a href=https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/>emacs</a> configuration that can somehow do everything. We also had a macOS rice built on top of <a href=https://github.com/koekeishiya/yabai>yabai</a>! Applications displayed included <a href=https://github.com/dylanaraps/neofetch>neofetch</a>, <a href=https://github.com/cmatsuoka/asciiquarium>asciiquarium</a>, and <a href=https://github.com/pipeseroni/pipes.sh>pipes.sh</a>. One of our members even wrote a <a href=https://github.com/wtheisen/BashDynamicPaper>dynamic wallpaper setter</a>, a useful tool for ricers.</p> <p>Click on some of our members’ screenshots below for inspiration for your own rice!</p> <p><a class=rice-sc href=https://yld.me/raw/gd9A.png> <img src=../assets/img/rice-fedora.png alt=Fedora rice> </a></p> <p><a class=rice-sc href=https://yld.me/raw/ayGp.png> <img src=../assets/img/rice-pop-1.png alt=Pop!_OS rice> </a></p> <p><a class=rice-sc href=https://yld.me/raw/buUV.png> <img src=../assets/img/rice-pop-2.png alt=Another Pop!_OS rice> </a></p> <p><a class=rice-sc href=https://yld.me/raw/c9sX.png> <img src=../assets/img/rice-macos.png alt=macOS rice> </a></p> <p><a class=rice-sc href=https://yld.me/raw/0Yj.png> <img src=../assets/img/rice-alpine.png alt=Alpine Linux rice> </a></p> <p><a class=rice-sc class=rice-sc1 href=https://yld.me/raw/eiTs.png> <img src=../assets/img/rice-arch.png alt=Arch Linux rice> </a></p> <style> .rice-sc { display: block; width: 700px; margin: 48px auto; } </style> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Advent of Code 2021</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-12-01-advent-of-code.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2021-12-01-advent-of-code.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>For our final meeting of the fall semester we discussed <a href=https://adventofcode.com/2021>Advent of Code</a>, an online Advent calendar of programming challenges which has gained large popularity.</p> <p>The daily puzzles come in two parts and become gradually more difficult as the month progresses. This presents a great opportunity to learn a new programming language, compete with others, or just have fun solving interesting problems. On the private leaderboard for NDLUG members, we had several people complete over half of the challenges!</p> <p>We wrote solutions in JavaScript, Python (normally and <a href=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_golf>code golfed</a>), Go, Swift, and Haskell, to name a few. Comparing problem-solving approaches and code snippets with each other made for lively discussion in our club’s <a href=https://regserv.ndlug.org/>IRC server</a>.</p> <p>Join us next year for AoC 2022!</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/advent-of-code.jpg alt=ASCII art Santa hat style=width:700px;border:3px solid red;></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Scribble the News</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-01-19-scribble-the-news.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-01-19-scribble-the-news.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In our first meeting of 2022, we tried a new idea: “Scribble the News,” a pictionary-like game in which we attempt to guess which open source news story is being drawn.</p> <p>Here are the news items we discussed:</p> <ol start=0 type=1> <li><a href=https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/12/minecraft-and-other-apps-face-serious-threat-from-new-code-execution-bug/>Zero-day in ubiquitous Log4j tool poses a grave threat to the Internet</a></li> <li><a href=https://9to5linux.com/ubuntu-21-04-hirsute-hippo-will-reach-end-of-life-on-january-20th-2022>Ubuntu 21.04 (Hirsute Hippo) Will Reach End of Life on January 20th, 2022</a></li> <li><a href=https://news.itsfoss.com/pop-os-21-10/>Pop!_OS 21.10 Introduces a New Application Library, GNOME 40, and a Refresh Install Option</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2021/12/ubuntu-22-04-yaru-theme-orange-refresh>Ubuntu 22.04 Theme Replaces Purple with Orange (Like, Everywhere)</a></li> <li><a href=https://news.itsfoss.com/solus-co-lead-resign-budgie-serpent/>Solus Linux Co-Lead Resigns, Joins Serpent OS and Plans to Fork Budgie Under a New Organization</a></li> <li><a href=https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=4244>Linux Mint Partners with Mozilla to ‘Improve Firefox Experience</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2021/12/red-hat-donates-10k-to-obs-studio-flatpak-to-be-official-for-linux/>Red Hat donates $10,000 to OBS Studio, their Flatpak to be official for Linux</a></li> <li><a href=https://news.itsfoss.com/wine-7-0-release/>Wine 7.0 is a Massive Upgrade with Improved Windows App Support, New Theme, and More Improvements</a></li> <li><a href=https://www.phoronix.com/forums/forum/phoronix/latest-phoronix-articles/1299874-steam-on-linux-ended-2021-at-1-11-marketshare>https://www.phoronix.com/forums/forum/phoronix/latest-phoronix-articles/1299874-steam-on-linux-ended-2021-at-1-11-marketshare</a></li> <li><a href=https://boilingsteam.com/all-roads-lead-to-arch-the-evolution-of-linux-distros-used-for-gaming-over-time/>All Roads Lead to Arch: The Evolution of Linux Distros Used for Gaming Over Time</a></li> </ol> <style> ol { font-size: 0.8em; margin: 32px auto; } li { margin: 1em auto; } </style> <p>Would you have guessed these from the drawings below?</p> <p><a href=https://yld.me/raw/fny4.pdf> <img src=../assets/img/scribble.png alt=Drawings of open source news style=width:700px;padding:5px;border:2px dotted black;margin:32px auto;> </a></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Battlestations</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-01-26-battlestations.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-01-26-battlestations.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>As a complement to our <a href=2021-11-17-ricing-unix.html>ricing showcase</a>, this week’s meeting featured a tour of our members’ battlestations. What is a battlestation? It’s how and where you do your computing, whether that’s a humble laptop at your desk or a custom-built gaming rig with multiple monitors and RGBs aplenty.</p> <p>For example, here is Linus Torvalds’ treadmill desk battlestation:</p> <p><img src=../assets/img/linus-treadmill-desk.png alt=Linus Torvalds and his desk treadmill></p> <p>See NDLUG’s battlestations in <a href=https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1vD5nqrlfaM4U5uXMFwIvdJ4XwPLweJK7LCwqiAV18DI/edit?usp=sharing>this presentation</a>.</p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Package Managers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-02-09-package-managers.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-02-09-package-managers.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>This meeting was our first in-person gathering of the semester, and pizza was back on the menu!</p> <p>LUG sysadmin Tom gave a brief presentation about package managers, which was followed by some discussion on the topic. Is pacman really so great? Is flatpak the future? Does the Python community really need to stop making new package management standards? Yes, maybe, and definitely yes!</p> <p>Slides are <a href=https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1z1vuycVW7Cw13861294V0p3wRAd_FBliRjpvXjBUJVg/edit#slide=id.p>here</a>.</p> <p><a href=https://xkcd.com/1742/> <img src=https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/will_it_work.png alt=XKCD 1742 style=width:284px> </a></p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Open Source Confessional</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Faughnan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-02-16-open-source-confessional.html"/>
        <updated>2022-02-21T14:28:28+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://ndlug.org/posts/2022-02-16-open-source-confessional.html</id>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Inspired by a recent episode of the <a href=https://linuxafterdark.net/linux-after-dark-episode-10/>Linux After Dark</a> podcast, we decided to discuss when it is reasonable (if ever) to submit to using non-FOSS solutions in our lives. Generally, all of us agreed that sometimes it is okay to be pragmatic and use proprietary software and devices, though to what extent was a point of contention.</p> <p>A large contingent of the club uses iPhones, for example, citing vendor lock-in and extolling the “just works” nature of Apple products. Is this forgivable?</p> <p>Some members debated whether gaming is an appropriate time to set aside one’s principles. Is playing closed-source video games on Linux an acceptable compromise, or should we reject this incongruence?</p> <p>Is fiddling around with free software always worth the hours out of your life? Everyone has a breaking point – what’s yours?</p> ]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>
